<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>develop on DevOps journey</title>
    <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/categories/develop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in develop on DevOps journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Matteo Guadrini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 15:44:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matteoguadrini.github.io/categories/develop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 15:44:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/tools/</guid>
      <description>Fedora: Welcome to Freedom Fedora is a Linux kernel based operating system. It offers three editions:
 Fedora Workstation, for all desktops and laptops Fedora Server, for any server Fedora IoT, for all ARM devices  It is also available in different variations, called spin. At this link you will find all the variants:
Fedora is a great operating system for operating on operating systems and programming with different languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Count the Code</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/count-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:55:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/count-the-code/</guid>
      <description>Measure the execution time Measuring the execution time of a script or program is part of a developer&amp;rsquo;s daily job.
It is not enough to see if it consumes too much memory or too much CPU. We need to see if the software in its entire life cycle is fast enough.
This is because the business logic of any software expects a certain task to be completed with a maximum time established by the programmer himself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux and Powershell</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/linux-and-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 12:15:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/linux-and-powershell/</guid>
      <description>What powershell? Powershell is an object-based shell born in Microsoft in 2006, made open source 10 years later. It is characterized by commands, called cmdlets, which respect a certain pattern. An example cmdlet is as follows:
Get-ChildItem -Path value The pattern in question is Verb-Noun -Option argument, where Verb is a list of verbs. Noun is a description of what impacts the command verb. The Option instead are preceded by a dash and its name; to follow, all the arguments of the option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Switch Story</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/a-switch-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 15:40:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/a-switch-story/</guid>
      <description>What is a switch? The switch is a statement that evaluates the accuracy or similarity of the value of a certain input. But isn&amp;rsquo;t that the same thing that the if statement does? Let&amp;rsquo;s see this statement starting with bash scripting language.
case EXPRESSION in PATTERN_1) STATEMENTS ;; PATTERN_2) STATEMENTS ;; PATTERN_N) STATEMENTS ;; *) STATEMENTS ;; esac EXPRESSION is an expression (command) or a variable. PATTERN_N, is a value that is expected from EXPRESSION.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
