<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matteo Guadrini&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Matteo Guadrini&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Matteo Guadrini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 14:54:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://matteoguadrini.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Containerized Python Development</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/containerized-python-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 14:54:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/containerized-python-development/</guid>
      <description>Developing python projects When we develop more than one python project, we need to configure our development environment with the dependencies of all the projects. This becomes even more complicated when there are many people on the development of the project. To do this, you need to create a development environment that is isolated from the others. We can do this thanks to docker containers.
Prepare project Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that our project has this structure:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Switch Story</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/a-switch-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 15:40:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/a-switch-story/</guid>
      <description>What is a switch? The switch is a statement that evaluates the accuracy or similarity of the value of a certain input. But isn&amp;rsquo;t that the same thing that the if statement does? Let&amp;rsquo;s see this statement starting with bash scripting language.
case EXPRESSION in PATTERN_1) STATEMENTS ;; PATTERN_2) STATEMENTS ;; PATTERN_N) STATEMENTS ;; *) STATEMENTS ;; esac EXPRESSION is an expression (command) or a variable. PATTERN_N, is a value that is expected from EXPRESSION.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Is Better Than Complex</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/simple-is-better-than-complex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 14:56:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/simple-is-better-than-complex/</guid>
      <description>&amp;hellip;and complex is better than complicated.
This has always been my motto. All my lines of code have simplicity as their primary goal.
I decided to start this blog, to tell about my IT adventures, to describe all my projects and experiences, so that they can help others.
Open Source To apply my motto, one of the principles that drives all my works, is the open source philosophy. Each of my projects is open source.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>