<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>system on DevOps journey</title>
    <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/categories/system/</link>
    <description>Recent content in system on DevOps journey</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Matteo Guadrini</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 15:44:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://matteoguadrini.github.io/categories/system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 15:44:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/tools/</guid>
      <description>Fedora: Welcome to Freedom Fedora is a Linux kernel based operating system. It offers three editions:
 Fedora Workstation, for all desktops and laptops Fedora Server, for any server Fedora IoT, for all ARM devices  It is also available in different variations, called spin. At this link you will find all the variants:
Fedora is a great operating system for operating on operating systems and programming with different languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automate Font Preview</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/automate-font-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 11:25:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/automate-font-preview/</guid>
      <description>In the life of a designer or font maker, the need arises to see how a font looks on a certain image, with a certain color and size, or simply, have a reliable preview of the final result. To do this, graphical tools are required.
Preview of a font To work with font previews, there are system previewers at the level of any operating system. This is a great starter tool to see what a font will look like on our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samba File Server</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/samba-file-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 15:31:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/samba-file-server/</guid>
      <description>Why a file server? One of the most common ways to network Linux and Windows computers is to configure Samba as a File Server. This section covers setting up a Samba server to share files with Windows clients.
Configure Samba First of all, you have to prepare your machine with everything you need. To do this server, I&amp;rsquo;m using a Fedora 33 server OS. Let&amp;rsquo;s start by installing the packages needed to make our server a Samba file server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen of Open Source</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/zen-of-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 10:26:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/zen-of-open-source/</guid>
      <description>Open philosophy When can a project be defined as open-source? When, as the word says, you open the source code and make it available to other people.
Of course, this is the first concept behind the open-source philosophy. But there is more.
Open source license To make a project open-source first, you need to release it with a certain license. In fact, there are a lot of them. They all share the main philosophy, but differ from each other in small points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Enterprise Backup</title>
      <link>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/linux-enterprise-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 14:17:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://matteoguadrini.github.io/posts/linux-enterprise-backup/</guid>
      <description>Why a backup is needed Having a backup system is necessary to ensure continuity to your systems, whatever work they do.
Backup systems can be simple if few machines are involved or complex in case there are hundreds of thousands of machines, such as in the cloud.
What to choose If your ecosystem includes a few machines, you will probably want to choose something simple .
A good and simple backup system is rsync.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
